Francheska Guzmán Flores

Software QA Testing and Automation Engineer

Carolina, PR | https://francheska.dev



About

Francheska has +9 years of combined experience in manual and automated software testing, quality assurance, and web development. ISTQB Certified Tester with strong analytical skills, problem solver, detail-oriented, and interpersonal abilities.

Skills

Technical Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Selenium, C#, .NET Framework, SpecFlow, NUnit, Docker, Cypress, Mocha, Gherkin Syntax, WordPress, React.js, Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Azure Test Plans, Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite (PowerMapper), Wave, Visual Studio, Microsoft SQL Server, Postman, Swagger.

Languages: Spanish (native), English (intermediate).

Work Experience

Abarca Health LLC - Pharmacy Benefit Manager (PBM)

San Juan, PR

Senior Software Testing Engineer

Apr 2024 - Present

- Contribute to updating and creating UI automated tests scenarios using Selenium with C#, .NET Framework, SpecFlow, NUnit, and Docker.
- Use GitKraken with Azure DevOps integration for a centralized Git workflow.
- Participate in the hiring process for Software Testing Engineering positions.
- Provide trainings to new hires about the internal QA processes, as well as walkthroughs of the Darwin web application.

Software Testing Engineer

Apr 2022 - Apr 2024

- Collaborate with Agile Team members and participate in the Scrum ceremonies.
- Develop test cases in Azure Test Plans based on business requirements and both functional and non-functional specifications.
- Use black-box testing techniques such as equivalence partitioning, boundary value analysis, and decision table testing to efficiently determine the parameters and data that will be added in Azure Test Plans to achieve full test coverage.
- Execute test cases and document the results.
- Inspect issues detected by using tools such as Hangfire, Datadog, and DevTools; and write detailed bug reports.
- Query execution over the Microsoft SQL Server database.
- Perform regression testing, compatibility testing, API testing (Postman and Swagger), and exploratory testing sessions.

INVID LLC - Information Technology Company Software QA Tester II

San Juan, PR

• Developed automated UI test scripts using Cypress, Cucumber, and Mocha.

- Contributed to the creation of guidelines to improve internal QA/QC procedures.
- Provided training about manual testing activities.

Software QA Tester I

Oct 2019 - Apr 2021

Apr 2021 - Apr 2022

- Performed static testing in requirements and design (mockups).
- Created test plans, test suites, and test cases in Azure Test Plans.
- Ran manual tests and performed exploratory testing in web and mobile applications.
- Conducted usability/accessibility testing for WCAG 2.1, ADA, and Section 508 compliance by using tools such as the Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Axe, SortSite, and Wave.
- Reported and tracked issues identified during testing activities to ensure defect resolution and testing completion.



- Collaborated in the development of new ideas to resolve system issues and improve current systems.
- Basic query execution over the Microsoft SQL Server database.

New York Film Academy - School of Film and Acting

New York, NY

Front End Web Developer

Jul 2018 - Aug 2019

- Coded e-mail marketing campaigns and landing pages based on mockups and provided content.
- Delivered approved e-mail campaigns to the target market using both Campaigner and iContact e-mail marketing automation platforms.
- Made updates to the New York Film Academy websites and WordPress sites.
- Coded the new version of the online applications.

Second Language Design - Creative and Marketing Agency Web Developer

New York, NY

Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

- Developed WordPress sites for clients based on mockups and provided content.
- Added meta tags for SEO and set up Google Analytics.
- Used Google Spreadsheets API for data collection.

uTest - Crowdsourced Software Testing Community Software Tester

Puerto Rico and New York

Sep 2014 - Jul 2018

- Executed test cases and performed exploratory testing sessions using a test charter.
- Performed localization testing by verifying translations from English to Latin American Spanish, geo-blocking validation, and so on.
- Tested +50 applications including eCommerce, games, transcription editors, financial, and streaming services.
- Acquired a foundation level of software testing and quality assurance through the uTest Academy.

Projects

Weather Forecast

https://francheska-guzman.github.io/weather-forecast

Weather Forecast is a web app that provides information such as temperature, pressure, and humidity of five cities. Developed with React.js and requesting the data from a third party API.

Education

CodeBridge - Web Development Immersive Program	New York, NY
Per Scholas and General Assembly, Certificate of Completion	Jun 2017
Bachelor of Business Administration	San Juan, PR
Accounting and Office Systems Administration, UPR Río Piedras	Jun 2015

Certifications

Certified Tester, Advanced Level Agile Technical Tester (CTAL-ATT) Nov 2022

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 22-CTAL-ATT-00026-USA

Certified Tester, Foundation Level Agile Tester (CTFL-AT) Apr 2022

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 22-CTFL-AT-00111-USA

Certified Tester, AT*SQA Testing Essentials

Association for Testing and Software Quality Assurance, Inc. (AT*SQA)

Credential ID: 21-AT*Essentials-00008-USA

Certified Tester, Foundation Level (CTFL)

Sep 2021

Dec 2021

International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Credential ID: 21-CTFL-01698-USA

Last Updated: June 2024